# Daniel Lupiañez Casares

Karl-Theodor-Straße 5, 22765 Hamburg GERMANY





+49 1575 7719413 M daniel.lupianez.casares@gmail.com



in LinkedIn profile



S daniel.lupianez.casares

#### **HIGHLIGHTS**

# Unity3D (2.5 years) iOS/tvOS (3 years)

# **SUMMARY**

Computer Engineer with a good academic background and experience in mobile and game development. Great sense of leadership, organization and responsibility. Abilities for project management and documentation. Confident to think through a problem and make ideas heard.

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### AREAS OF EXPERTISE

Unity3D, Game Maker Studio

iOS, tvOS

C#, Objective C, Swift, Java

Git, JSON, XML, REST

C, C++

Cocoapods

UML

Xcode

Visual Studio/ Visual Studio Code

Mobile applications & games

Requirements gathering

Unit testing

## Senior iOS Game Developer - Xyrality GmbH.

07/2015 - 09/2016

Software design ♦ Objective C and Swift programming ♦ Error analysis and bug fixing ◆ New features implementation ◆ 3rd party SDKs integration and maintenance ◆ Code review ◆ tvOS Project ◆ App uploading ◆ Code optimization ◆ Unit test development

### Indie Game Developer - Self employed

07/2013 - 07/2015

Improve Game Maker Studio skills ♦ Learn Unity3D & improve skills ♦ Plugin development ◆ Local multiplayer in Android and iOS using AllJoyn libraries ◆ Google AdMob integration ◆ Google Play Services & Game Center integration ◆ Game publishing on Play Store and App Store ♦ Trailer and screenshot creation

# iOS Lead Developer - Verified Learning S.L.

12/2012 - 07/2013

Software design, planning and development of the Verified LMS iOS App ◆ API service design and adaptation ◆ Communication protocol design between server and main app ♦ App integration with main system

#### Junior Mobile App Developer - ObjectiveTouch S.L.

09/2011 - 08/2012

Learn Objective C, iOS SDK and Android SDK ◆ Assist in project analysis and design phases ♦ Write code for developed apps ♦ Create reusable modules for apps ♦ Code documentation ♦ Debugging and troubleshooting.

#### **PERSONAL SKILLS**

Flexible and adaptable

Fast learner

Problem solver

Creative and imaginative

Team communicative

#### **EDUCATION**

#### **University of Granada**

Master in Computer Science and Engineering 2005-2011

### Lappeenranta University of Technology

Erasmus International Mobility Program (MA in Information Technology) 2010-2011

#### **Courses**

- ◆ Digital Animation and Augmented Reality (30 h)
- ◆ Ubiquitous Computation and Intelligent Environments (30 h)
- ◆ CodeCamp Microsoft .NET (Imagine Cup 2011) (72 h)
- ◆ Project "2D/3D tracking using Wilmote" (250 h) ~ Video

#### **OTHER**

◆ 2nd place at Granada's Campus InWatch hackathon. Developed a helper app to quit smoking (February 2015) ~ Video

#### **LANGUAGES**

Spanish (Native) ◆ English (C1) ◆ French (A1)

**REFERENCES** (Available on request)

# PORTFOLIO AND PROJECTS



Github profile

You can check some of my code snippets and coding style in my public profile.

# Unity3D



Butano Racer (iOS & Android) 12/2014 Game created using Unity 3D in a limited amount of time applying some skills I learned. It includes AdMob integration and Google Play Games/Game Center for highscores and achievements.



Football GO! (iOS & <u>Android</u>) 2014 [Unpublished] Serverless multiplayer prototype using AllJoyn. It allowed to play between iOS and Android devices. Multiplayer service is implemented natively for iOS and Android.

Food Galaxy (iOS & <u>Android</u>) 2013-2014 [Unpublished] Screenshots: #1 #2 #3 #4

Platformer prototype with special focus on gravity physics. Enhances Unity Physics2D engine to adapt to gameplay. Players can jump from planet to planet seamlessly.

Web version Screenshots: #1 #2 #3 #4

# iOS/tvOS





Lords & Knights Lords & Knights Xmas 07/2015 - 09/2016 Realtime medieval strategy MMO game based on UIKit. Since it was launched in June of 2011, it has over 12 million downloads.



<u>Celtic Tribes</u> (iOS & tvOS) 07/2015 - 09/2016 Realtime strategy MMO game based on UIKit and SpriteKit. Over 3.5 million downloads. Ported to tvOS.



<u>Crazy Tribes</u> 07/2015 - 09/2016

Realtime strategy MMO game based on UIKit. Over 2 million downloads.



<u>Imperial Dynasties</u> 07/2015 - 09/2016

Realtime strategy MMO game based on UIKit.



Growcrowd (v 1.0) 04/2013 - 09/2013

A side project proposed by an entrepeneur. It allowed individuals to sell their homegrown vegetables to other people in the nearby area.



Verified LMS (iPhone & iPad) 12/2012 - 07/2013 To use with the Verified learning platform. List courses, take courses, take tests, generate certificates. Watch videos and listen to audios in the courses. It is now known as WCE LMS.



iPresentations (iPad) 04/2012-06/2012 Create presentations using the iPad as a canvas for images, videos, sounds and rich formatted text. Some tutorials are uploaded on <u>youtube</u>. It is now removed from the App Store.



BPlus (iPhone) 01-2012 An unpublished prototype. Retrieve stock market data in real time using Yahoo Query Language, show graphs and piecharts, and set up alerts for stock values.



Bollettino (v 1.0) (iPhone & iPad) 10/2011-12/2011 For PosteItaliane, allows italian citizens to pay their bills using their mobile phones. It contains a datamatrix reader to scan the codes present in the bills.

#### **Android**



Farmagraph (Android) 06/2012-08/2012

For the pharmaceutical industry. It tracks agent activity and play presentations downloaded from the cloud. App only available upon request and meeting.